Register of the Alexander Liosnoff papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Alexander Liosnoff papers
1935-2005
2005C19
Hoover Institution Archives
44 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes, 1 cubic foot box (17.8 linear feet)
The papers contain information on the Shanghai American School Association, American psychological warfare activities during the Korean War, and the post-World War II American civil administration of the Ryukyu Islands, based in Okinawa, including reversion to Japan in 1972. The materials were generally kept in the original order and arrangement of the creator.
Liosnoff, Alexander, 1920-
Access
The collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2005.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1920, May 7 Born, Harbin, Manchuria
1938 Graduated, Shanghai American School
1941 Graduated, University of Missouri School of Journalism
1941-1943 Radio news reporter and editor, KMOX-CBS St. Louis, Missouri
1943-1946 Drafted; Served in the U.S. Army in World War II
1946-1950 Radio news reporter and editor, KLX-Oakland Tribune, Oakland, California, and KGO-ABC, San Francisco, California
1950-1951 Recalled to serve in the Korean War, GHQ Far East Command, duty with Psychological Warfare Branch G2 and Radio Pusan
1951-1957 United States Army Seventh Psychological Operations Group and First Radio Broadcasting and Leaflet Group
1957-1971 Chief, Information Division, Public Affairs Department, U.S. Civil Administration of the Ryukyu Islands, Okinawa
1971-1972 Director, Public Affairs Department, U.S. Civil Administration of the Ryukyu Islands, Okinawa
1972-1985 Consultant in public affairs, Bank of America Communications Department, San Francisco
1985 Retired
1989-1991 First president, Shanghai American School Association
1989-1998 Newsletter editor, Shanghai American School Association
Scope and Content of Collection
Acquired in 2005, the Alexander Liosnoff Papers contain information about the Shanghai American School Association, American psychological warfare activities during the Korean War, and the post-World War II American civil administration of Okinawa and the Ryukyu Islands, including reversion to Japan in 1972. Materials were kept in the original order and arrangement of the creator.
The Korea Files document the Army's Psychological Operations, focusing on radio broadcasting to South and North Korea via Radio Pusan. Documents collected include information gathered in both Korea and Tokyo on psychological warfare, the management of prisoners of war, and propaganda leaflets. Oversize Materials contains a photograph album about Korea.
The Okinawa Files (U.S. Civil Administration of the Ryukyu Islands) include correspondence, reports, memoranda, press releases, press summaries, radio broadcast scripts, studies, reports, newsletters, clippings, printed materials, and photographs, documenting the administration and local relationships of the public affairs staff of the U.S. Civil Administration of the Ryukyus from 1957 to the reversion of the territory to Japan in 1972. Oversize Materials include photographs and photograph albums documenting Okinawa. Printed Matter contains numerous secondary sources on Okinawa.
Shanghai American School Association (SASA) Records are comprised of materials documenting the activities of Shanghai American School (SAS) alumni. Liosnoff served as the founding president and newsletter editor from 1989-1998. Documents include information about the executive board, correspondence, newsletters, and annual reunions. Oversize Material includes a photograph album of SASA activities, while Printed Matter contains published works of former SAS students.
The Oral History Materials series includes an audio tape and transcript of an oral history interview with Alexander Liosnoff. Conducted by Brad Bauer, Associate Archivist for Collection Development at the Hoover Institution Archives in 2005, the interview connects the materials in the collections with the events in Liosnoff's life.
Arrangement
Organized into six series: Oral History Materials, Shanghai American School Association Records, Korea Files, Okinawa Files (U.S. Civil Administration of the Ryukyu Islands), Oversize Materials, and Printed Matter.
Shanghai American School Association.; Shanghai American School.; United States. Army.; Americans--China.; Education--China.; Korean War, 1950-1953--Prisoners and prisons.; Korean War, 1950-1953--Propaganda.; Korean War, 1950-1953--Psychological aspects.; Okinawa-ken (Japan); Prisoners of war.; Propaganda, American--Korea (North); Radio broadcasting--Korea (North); Ryukyu Islands (United States Civil Administration, 1945-1972); Ryukyu Islands--History--1945-1972.; Shanghai (China)
- Oral History Materials, 2005
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes audio recording and transcript of a 2005 oral history interview with Alexander Liosnoff conducted by Brad Bauer, the Hoover Institution Archives Associate Archivist for Collection Development.
  - Compact sound cassettes, 2005 October 3 (Box-folder 1: 1)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Use copy reference number: 2005C119_a_0000077_a
  - Transcripts, 2005 (Box-folder 1: 2-3)
- Shanghai American School Association (SASA) Records, 1935-2004
  General note
  See also Oversize Materials for a Photograph Album.
  Contains documentation on the school as well as records, correspondence, and newsletters of the association. Documents include materials of the executive board, officers, and information about annual reunions. Arranged into groups by function.
  - Historical, 1935-2000 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - New School, 1980-1995 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Administrative correspondence, American Consulate General, Shanghai, 1997 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Plans and goals, 1991 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Songs, undated (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Formation, 1989 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - Executive committee
    - Meetings, 1989-1994 (Box-folder 2: 5-6)
    - Activities, 1990 (Box-folder 2: 7)
      Includes Chinese mayor's visit to U.S.
    - Correspondence
      - Liosnoff, Alexander, 1979-2001 (Box-folder 2: 8-11)
      - General, 1991-2003 (Box-folder 2: 12)
      - Armstrong, Oscar, 1989-2002 (Box-folder 3: 1)
        Executive committee
      - Arnold, Jack, 1989-2004 (Box-folder 3: 2)
      - Barr, Betty, 1989-2003 (Box-folder 3: 3)
        Shanghai news correspondent
      - Belknap, Ted, officer, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 3: 4)
        Class of 1940 aide
      - Campbell, Ruth Creighton, 1992-2003 (Box-folder 3: 5)
        Newsletter artist
      - Cavanaugh, Jim, 1989-1995 (Box-folder 3: 6)
        Class representative, 1948-1951
      - Gallimore, Bob, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 3: 7)
        Officer
      - Harnsberger, Jim, 1991-1995 (Box-folder 3: 8)
        President, officer
      - Hazzard, Mike, 1986-1995 (Box-folder 3: 9)
      - Heinrichsohn, Theodor (Teddy), 1992-2004 (Box-folder 3: 10)
        President
      - Hoffman, Jim, 1989-1997 (Box-folder 3: 11)
      - Jordan, Faison (Bill), 1989-1990 (Box-folder 3: 12)
      - Jorgensen, Lorents (Larry), 1988-1998 (Box-folder 4: 1)
        Class representative, 1940
      - Karegeannes, Carrie, 1992-2002 (Box-folder 4: 2)
      - Krisel, Lionel, 1977-1999 (Box-folder 4: 3-4)
        President, treasurer
      - Locke, Harriet, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 4: 5)
        Class representative, 1950 and later, Peace Corps
      - McAllister, Mary Frances Espey, 1990-1995 (Box-folder 4: 6)
        Class representative, 1927 and earlier
      - McClure, George, 1987-1997 (Box-folder 4: 7)
      - McKeever, Susan L., 1986-1991 (Box-folder 4: 8)
      - Mills, Angie, 1989-2003 (Box-folder 4: 9)
        News editor, class representative, 1942
      - Namey, Mary W., 1986-1999 (Box-folder 4: 10)
        Class representative, 1938
      - Pryor, Lois, 1991-2002 (Box-folder 4: 11)
      - Romasco, Anne, 2003 (Box-folder 4: 12)
      - Stannard, Jean, 1990-1998 (Box-folder 4: 13)
        Class representative, 1941
      - Stannard, Ted, 1993-2003 (Box-folder 4: 14)
      - Walker, Millidge, 1991-1998 (Box-folder 5: 1)
      - Wentworth, Phoebe, 1988-2001 (Box-folder 5: 2)
      - Wiant, Al, 1994-2003 (Box-folder 5: 3-4)
      - Witts, Pauline, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 5: 5)
      - Biographies, 1986-2001, undated (Box-folder 5: 6-8)
  - SASA Correspondence
    - Barnett, A. Doak, 1950-1996 (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - Crum, Guy and Bill, 1966, 1991 1994 (Box-folder 6: 2)
    - Espey, John, 1991-2000 (Box-folder 6: 3)
    - Fox, Don, 1990, 1998 (Box-folder 6: 4)
    - Freeman Foundation, Houghton (Buck) Freeman, 1987-2003 (Box-folder 6: 5)
    - Furnas, Wendell, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 6: 6)
    - Greenhut, Barry, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 6: 7)
    - Hanson, William L., 1990, 1996 (Box-folder 6: 8)
    - Herman, Ted, 1994-1998 (Box-folder 6: 9)
    - Horton, Dr. Tony, 1990-2000 (Box-folder 6: 10)
    - Hsu, Ming Chen, 1990-2000 (Box-folder 6: 11)
    - Isham, Molly, 1992-2002 (Box-folder 6: 12)
    - Lilley, James R., 1989-2004 (Box-folder 6: 13)
      Former Ambassador to China, includes micro cassette
    - Montgomery, Ronald, 1990-1999 (Box-folder 6: 14)
      Includes photographs
    - Noyes, Dorothy Stannard, 1995-1998 (Box-folder 7: 1)
    - Overholt, Martin, 1999 (Box-folder 7: 2)
    - Peretz, Dwight I., 1994-1995 (Box-folder 7: 3)
    - Rohe, Terry, 1985-1993 (Box-folder 7: 4)
    - Root, Kapsy Russel and Charles, 1992-1999 (Box-folder 7: 5)
    - Roy, Ambassador J. Stapleton, 1991-2003 (Box-folder 7: 6)
    - Schmid, Beth Louis, 1988-1998 (Box-folder 7: 7)
    - Schmidt, Eric, 1991-1997 (Box-folder 7: 8)
    - Service, Jack, 1973 (Box-folder 7: 9)
    - Silver, Pat Dunn, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 7: 10)
    - Smith, Huston, 1982-1997 (Box-folder 7: 11)
      Includes a photograph
    - Smith, Walt, 1988-1992 (Box-folder 7: 12)
    - Stamps, George and Helen, 1991 (Box-folder 7: 13)
    - Stimpson, Mary Bills, 1994 (Box-folder 7: 14)
    - Stocker, Hugh Marion, 1989-1990 1996 (Box-folder 7: 15)
    - Tappan, David S., 1989-1991 2002 (Box-folder 7: 16)
    - Wallace, Barbara Brooks, 1994 (Box-folder 7: 17)
    - Wampler, Joe, 1990-1996 (Box-folder 7: 18)
    - Williams, Dan, 1988-2001 (Box-folder 7: 19)
    - Wilson, Pete, 1991 (Box-folder 7: 20)
      Former Governor of California
  - Reunions
    - Class of 1938, 1986-1999 (Box-folder 7: 21)
      Includes yearbook copies and California license plate, SASA 38
    - 1986, Asilomar, California (Box-folder 7: 22)
    - 1987, Hershey, Pennsylvania (Box-folder 7: 23)
    - 1988, Santa Rosa, California, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 8: 1-6)
    - 1988, Santa Rosa, California (Box-folder 9: 1)
    - 1989, 1994, Williamsburg, Virginia, 1989, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 9: 2)
      Includes micro cassette of Ambassador Lilley's speech in 1994
    - 1989 for post-war classes, Culver City, California (Box-folder 9: 3)
    - 1990, Class of 1940, Washington, D.C. (Box-folder 9: 4)
    - 1990, China Camp State Park, San Francisco, California (Box-folder 9: 5)
    - 1991, San Diego, California (Box-folder 9: 6-10)
    - 1992, Kansas City, Missouri (Box-folder 9: 11)
    - 1994, Williamsburg, Virginia
      (see 1989 file)
    - 1997, Sarasota, Florida (Box-folder 9: 12)
    - 2000, Roslyn, Virginia (Box-folder 9: 13)
    - 2002, Gatlinburg, Tennessee, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 10: 1)
    - 2003, Orlando, Florida, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 10: 2-4)
      Includes panel preparations
    - Old China Hands Reunions, 1990-1996, undated (Box-folder 10: 5)
  - Chronological Correspondence
    - 1990 (Box-folder 10: 6-7)
    - 1991-1993 (Box-folder 11: 1-6)
    - 1994 (Box-folder 12: 1)
    - 1992-1994 (Box-folder 12: 2)
  - Notes, 1992-1999 (Box-folder 12: 3)
  - Newsletter
    - SASA News, 1989-Fall 2004 (Box-folder 12: 4-5)
    - Correspondence
      - 1990 (Box-folder 12: 6)
      - 1992 (Box-folder 12: 7)
      - 1993 (Box-folder 13: 1-5)
      - 1994 (Box-folder 13: 6-7)
      - 1997 (Box-folder 13: 8-11)
      - 1997-1998 (Box-folder 14: 1-3)
    - Mockups, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 14: 4)
  - Miscellany, 1937-2005 (Box-folder 14: 5)
  - SASA Additional Materials, 1938-2009
    - Shanghai American School (SAS) diploma, 1938 (Box-folder 40: 1)
    - SAS felt letters, circa 1938 (Box-folder 40: 2)
    - Appointment calendars, 1995-1996, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 40: 3)
    - Biographies, 1994 (Box-folder 40: 4)
    - Photographs, 1991-1994 (Box-folder 40: 5)
    - SASA publications correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 40: 6)
    - Directory, 1999 (Box-folder 40: 7)
    - Newsletters, 1989-1998 (Box-folder 40: 8)
    - Reunion videos, 1994, 1998 (Box 47)
    - SAS audio tape, G.H. Stocker, undated (Box 47)
    - "China Memoirs," prepared for the SAS reunion, Oct-02 (Box-folder 40: 9)
    - Dripping with Nostalgia: China, 1900-1937, typescript by Hugh Stocker, 1998 (Box-folder 40: 10)
    - Shanghai, by Harriet Sergeant, 1991 (Box-folder 40: 11)
    - Supplementary materials to the Shanghai book by Lynn Pan (Box-folder 40: 12-13)
    - Shanghai: A century of change in photographs 1843-1949 by Lynn Pan, reviews, 2009 (Box-folder 40: 14)
    - Shanghai: A century of change in photographs 1843-1949 by Lynn Pan, 1995 (Box 41)
- Korea Files, 1951-1962
  See also Oversize Materials for photograph album of Pusan, South Korea, and Japan, 1951-1957.
  consists of radio program scripts, interviews, reports, press releases, leaflets, flyers, and clippings about radio broadcasting, prisoners of war, psychological warfare, and propaganda during the Korean War. Arranged by physical form.
  - Psywar operations, programs, 1951-1967 (Box-folder 15: 1)
  - Radio station HLKA, Pusan, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 15: 2)
  - News commentaries scripts, 1951-1956 (Box-folder 15: 3)
  - Prisoner of war taped interview transcripts, 1952 (Box-folder 15: 4)
  - Major Joo Yong Bok, 1952-1993 (Box-folder 15: 5)
  - Prisoner of war camps, 1951-1956 (Box-folder 15: 6)
  - Official reports on prisoners of war, 1953, 1956 (Box-folder 15: 7)
  - Press releases, and wire services teletypes, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 15: 8)
  - Propaganda analyses, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 15: 9)
  - Leaflets, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 15: 10)
    In Korean, Russian, and Japanese
  - Leaflets, posters, and news sheets, circa 1951-1954 (Box-folder 15: 11-12)
    In Korean and Russian
  - Korean War armistice, 1951-1954 (Box-folder 15: 13)
  - Survey of China mainland press source material, 1953 (Box-folder 15: 14)
  - Korea, general publications, 1951-1962 (Box-folder 15: 15)
  - Korea Files Additional Materials, 1937-2005
    - Psywar Korea leaflets, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 41: 1)
    - Psywar Korea press and analysis, 1952-1955 (Box-folder 41: 2-3)
    - Korean War Speech materials, 1952-2007 (Box-folder 41: 4)
    - John William (Bill) Powell, 1952-1982 (Box-folder 41: 5)
    - Kenneth Wu (military interpreter) correspondence, 1951-2005 (Box-folder 41: 6-7)
    - Japan collected materials, 1945-1987 (Box-folder 41: 8)
    - China and Chinese language collected materials, 1937-1953 (Box-folder 41: 9)
    - Military Intelligence Service Association of Northern California, 1998-2006 (Box-folder 41: 10)
    - Freeman Foundation and Military Intelligence Association documentary, 1965-2009 (Box-folder 41: 11)
- Okinawa Files (U.S. Civil Administration of the Ryukyu Islands), 1950-2001
  See also Oversize Materials for photographs and photo albums, and Printed Matter for secondary sources.
  includes briefings, treaties, agreements, reports, news releases, articles, speeches, surveys, correspondence, photographs, and printed materials on the military, reversion process, politics, economics, history, social conventions, cultural arts, and news media of Okinawa and the Ryukyu Islands. Photographs may be found throughout the series where noted. Arranged into groups by subject.
  - Overview Materials
    - Briefings, treaties, and executive orders, 1951, 1957-1971 (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - Briefings, U.S. Civil Administration of the Ryukyu Islands, 1960-1972, 1992, 1999 (Box-folder 16: 2)
      Briefings and mission organization
    - GRI (Government of the Ryukyu Islands), 1957-1972, 2000 (Box-folder 16: 3)
    - Legal documentation, 1957-1973 (Box-folder 16: 4)
    - Fact sheets and fact books, 1962-1963, 1972 (Box-folder 16: 5)
    - Okinawa Briefings, 1962-1971 (Box-folder 17: 1)
    - U.S. - Japan mutual security policy, 1955-1972, 1992, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 17: 2)
    - Geopolitical information, published Japanese opinions, 1962-1973, 1996 (Box-folder 17: 3)
    - News conferences, interviews, 1960-1970 (Box-folder 17: 4)
    - Special Action Committee on Okinawa (SACO) report, 1996 (Box-folder 17: 5)
    - Organizational chart, 1971 (Box-folder 17: 6)
  - Military
    - Bases, 1964-1972, 1990-2000 (Box-folder 17: 7)
    - Futenma base, 1996-2001 (Box-folder 17: 8)
    - Land acquisition, 1955-1970 (Box-folder 18: 1)
    - Image incidents, 1959-1971, 1991-2000 (Box-folder 18: 2)
    - Gas and nuclear weapons, 1965-1972, 1999 (Box-folder 18: 3)
    - 1945 Battle of Okinawa, 1945-1967, 1987-2000
  - Reversion
    - Committees and commissions, 1965-1971 (Box-folder 18: 4)
    - Agreements, 1965-1974, 2000 (Box-folder 18: 5)
    - Cultural centers, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 19: 1)
    - Bank of the Ryukyus, 1960 1971-1972 (Box-folder 19: 2)
    - Articles on Reversion Actions, 1961-1973 (Box-folder 19: 3)
    - Historical, 1964-1974 (Box-folder 19: 4)
  - Political
    - G-8 Summit 2000, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 19: 5)
    - General, 1964-1974 (Box-folder 19: 6)
    - Prime Minister Sato, 1965-1973 (Box-folder 19: 7)
    - Masahide Ota writings and clippings, 1965-1968, 1984, 1990-2001 (Box-folder 19: 8)
    - Masahide Ota visit to U.S. documentation, 1998 (Box-folder 19: 9)
    - Masahide Ota correspondence, 1967-2000 (Box-folder 20: 1-2)
    - Dr. Mikio Higa articles and correspondence, 1962-2005 (Box-folder 20: 3-4)
    - President Eisenhower visit to Okinawa, 19 June 1960 (Box-folder 20: 5)
    - Elections, 1952-1970, 2000 (Box-folder 20: 6)
    - Messages from the U.S. High Commissioner to the Government of the Ryukyu Islands, 1959-1968 (Box-folder 20: 7)
    - Senkaku Retto (in Japanese) or Diao-Yu Tai (in Chinese) Islands, 1972-1974, 1982, 1990-2000 (Box-folder 20: 8)
    - Political opinion publications
      - Ryukyuan, 1957-1972, 1989-1997 (Box-folder 21: 1)
      - Japanese, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 21: 2)
      - American, 1957-1972 (Box-folder 21: 3)
  - Economic
    - General, 1957-1972, 2000 (Box-folder 21: 4)
    - Reports, 1959-1970 (Box-folder 21: 5)
    - U.S. financial contributions, 1959-1971 (Box-folder 21: 6)
    - Bank of America, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 22: 1)
    - Expo '75, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 22: 2)
    - Tourism, 1960-2000, undated (Box-folder 22: 3)
    - Busena Resort Corporation, Site of G-8 Summit, circa 2000 (Box-folder 22: 4)
    - Labor, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 22: 5)
    - Petroleum, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 22: 6)
    - N.S. Savannah, 1956-1968 (Box-folder 22: 7)
      Atomic powered merchant ship visit
    - Junior Chamber International conference, 1963 (Box-folder 22: 8)
    - Pacific Festival, Kyuyo Maru, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 22: 9)
    - Hawaii immigration, 1963-1965, 1982-2000 (Box-folder 23: 1)
  - Social
    - Public health, 1961 1971-1972 (Box-folder 23: 2)
    - Education and welfare, 1962-1972, 1992, 2000 (Box-folder 23: 3)
    - University of the Ryukyus, 1961-1962, 1972, 1992 (Box-folder 23: 4)
    - Golden Gate Club, 1952-1969 (Box-folder 23: 5)
    - Culture, 1960-1973, 1987-1995, 2000 (Box-folder 23: 6)
    - Cultural arts and dance, 1958-1960, 1974-2000 (Box-folder 23: 7)
    - Crafts, 1965-1971, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 24: 1)
    - Rites and festivals, 1962-1971, 2000 (Box-folder 24: 2)
  - U.S. Civil Administration of the Ryukyu Islands (USCAR) Public Affairs
    - Policies and operations, 1958-1972 (Box-folder 24: 3)
    - Projects, 1951-1972 (Box-folder 24: 4)
    - News media correspondence, 1958-1972 (Box-folder 24: 5)
    - General correspondence, 1967-1996 (Box-folder 24: 6)
    - News media file, 1953-1979 (Box-folder 25: 1-2)
    - Konnichi No Ryukyu (Ryukus Today) magazine, 1957-1970 (Box-folder 25: 3)
      See also Printed Matter.
  - Historical
    - Bibliography, gazetteer, 1923-2001, undated (Box-folder 25: 4)
      Includes maps
    - Commodore Perry, Dr. Bettelheim, 1882-1937 (Box-folder 25: 5)
      Photographic copies of historical correspondence
    - Commodore Matthew C. Perry, U.S. Navy, 1945-1971, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 25: 6)
    - General Historical, 1945-2000 (Box-folder 25: 7)
    - General Historical, 1945-2000 (Box-folder 26: 1)
    - Political surveys and polls, 1958-1971 (Box-folder 26: 2)
    - Surveys, 1958-1971 (Box-folder 26: 3)
  - News Releases
    - April-October 1960 (Box-folder 26: 4-8)
    - November-December 1960 (Box-folder 27: 1)
    - January-May 1971 (Box-folder 27: 2-5)
    - November 1971 - May 1972 (Box-folder 27: 6-7)
  - Press Office
    - Public Affairs Department, U.S. Civil Administration of the Ryukyus, 1960-1972, 1999 (Box-folder 27: 8)
      Includes photographs, reports, and clippings
    - Ryukyu Press Group visits the government information office of China, 1969 (Box-folder 28: 1)
    - High Commissioner and Civil Administrator speech texts, 1960-1972 (Box-folder 28: 2)
    - Japanese views: Okinawa press translations, 1961-1967 (Box-folder 28: 3)
  - Correspondence
    - News media, 1950-1973, 1987-2000 (Box-folder 28: 4-5)
    - General, 1957-1973, 1990-2004 (Box-folder 28: 6-7)
    - Invitations, letters, cards and notes, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 29: 1-2)
    - Freimuth, Edward, 1957-2001 (Box-folder 29: 3)
    - Kabira, Kiyoshi, 1967-1984 (Box-folder 29: 4)
      Includes clippings
    - Martin, James V., 1973-2004 (Box-folder 29: 5)
      Political advisor to the U.S. high commissioner of the Ryukyu Islands
    - Miyagi, Etsujiro, 1973-1978, 1966 (Box-folder 29: 6)
    - Najkachi, Masao, 1997-2003 (Box-folder 29: 7)
      Includes photograph. See also Ota, Masahide
    - Okinawan prefecture government scholars visit, 1997 (Box-folder 29: 8)
    - Ota, Masahide, 1967-2001 (Box-folder 29: 9)
    - Sutu, T. T., K. S. Hsia, W. Kuai, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 29: 10)
      Personal correspondence
  - Photographs
    - Government, 1952-2000 (Box-folder 29: 11)
    - USCAR prints of economic situations, 1950-1971 (Box-folder 29: 12)
    - Cultural, Educational, Social, 1958-1965 (Box-folder 29: 13)
    - Visit by Chief Executive Jugo Thoma to the Department of the Army, Washington, D.C., 1958 June-July (Box-folder 29: 14)
  - Clippings
    - Okinawan Reversion clippings, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 30: 1-2)
      In Japanese and English
    - Clippings, circa 1960-1999 (Box-folder 30: 3)
    - Japanese newspapers, 1969-1973, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 30: 4)
    - Newspapers: Japanese Declare War, Japanese Surrender, 1941-1945 (Box-folder 30: 5)
  - Printed Materials
    - Directory of Key Ryukyuan Personnel, Research and Evaluation Division, Public Affairs Department, U.S. Civil Administration of the Ryukyu Islands, 1969
    - Government of the Ryukyu Islands: Biographical Information, U.S. Civil Administration of the Ryukyu Islands, Liaison Department, 1969